

# Varvara Lazarenko

Address Telephone

Nijmegen, The Netherlands +31 6 2662 9839 **E-mail** varlazoa@gmail.com

Date of birth 29.12.1998 (26 years) LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly motivated and hardworking graduate with a Master's degree in Medical biology. Having worked in a fundamental research setting as well as in clinical trials development, I am passionate about the business and societal aspects of innovations. With a strong biomedical foundation and a keen interest in disseminating knowledge, I envision a career in consultancy or project management.

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2022 - 08/2024

# MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA 7.63/10.00
- ✓ Principal subjects: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Reaching the Sustainable **Development Goals**
- ✓ Projects: «HTA of a Medical Guidance App for International Students in the NL» «A Shared Ownership Model of the Green Corridor, Nijmegen»
  - «A Circular Alternative to Single-Use Cups Within the Dutch Train System»
- ✓ Master thesis: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care»

09/2016 - 06/2020

# BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Specialisation: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA 4.83/5.00
- ✓ Principal subjects: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Microbiology, Genetics, Biochemistry, Biophysics, Immunology, Embryology
- ✓ <u>Skills</u>: PCR, gel electrophoresis, wire myography, western blotting, ELISA, immunohistochemistry, intracellular recording (microelectrodes, patch clump), behaviour testing (open field test, elevated plus maze, light-dark box test)
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats»

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

02/2024 - 08/2024

#### **Intern at Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care**

# **HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands**

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- √ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023

#### **Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory**

# **Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands**

- ✓ In vivo Ca<sup>2+</sup> imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (mice, handling & feeding, craniotomy)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

# 08/2021 - 08/2022 Assistant at the Science department of the Contract Research Organization LABMGMU, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- ✓ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Advising on the number & design of (pre-)clinical studies for companies
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

#### 10/2020 - 10/2021

### Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

#### Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological (wire myography technique, rat coronary and renal arteries) and molecular (RNA extraction, reverse transcription, qPCR) experiments
- √ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats: housing, care, breeding)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at the <u>virtual conference ARTERY20</u>, 23-24 October 2020, and at the <u>28th International Scientific Conference "Lomonosov-2021"</u>, 12-23 April 2021

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, Rotor-Gene Q Series , and MS Office softwares

#### **LANGUAGES**

Russian (native), English (fluent –  $C_2$ ), German (intermediate –  $B_1$ - $B_2$ ), Dutch (low intermediate –  $A_2$ - $B_1$ ), French (beginner -  $A_1$ )

#### **ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS**

- 2022-2024 Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
- 2020-2021 Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
  - 2021 Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- 2023 A course on ex. Art. 9 of the Dutch Act on animal experimentation, Radboudumc
- 2021 An upgrade training on ICH GCP guidelines, LABMGMU

## **VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY**

- 2024 Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
- 2023 Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
- 2022-2023 Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
- 2018-2021 Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

#### **HOBBIES**

Volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

# **JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., **Lazarenko Varvara S.**, Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. *Frontiers in physiology*, *13*: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- **2. Lazarenko Varvara**, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. *Artery Research*, *26*(S1): S58. <a href="https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048">https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048</a>
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., **Lazarenko V.S.**, Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. *Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina*, *54*(2): 89–95. <a href="https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639">https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639</a>